{"test_questions": [[{"question": "When he\n\n\n\nP :\n did not know\n\n\n\nQ :\n he was nervous and\n\n\n\nR :\n heard the hue and cry at midnight\n\n\n\nS :\n what to do\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RQPS", "optb": "QSPR", "optc": "SQPR", "optd": "PQRS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It has been established that\n\n\n\nP :\n Einstein was\n\n\n\nQ :\n although a great scientist\n\n\n\nR :\n weak in arithmetic\n\n\n\nS :\n right from his school days\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRPQ", "optb": "QPRS", "optc": "QPSR", "optd": "RQPS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Then\n\n\n\nP :\n it struck me\n\n\n\nQ :\n of course\n\n\n\nR :\n suitable it was\n\n\n\nS :\n how eminently\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SPQR", "optb": "QSRP", "optc": "PSRQ", "optd": "QPSR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I read an advertisement that said\n\n\n\nP :\n posh, air-conditioned\n\n\n\nQ :\n gentleman of taste\n\n\n\nR :\n are available for \n\n\n\nS :\n fully furnished rooms\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "PSRQ", "optc": "PSQR", "optd": "SRPQ", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Since the beginning of history \n\n\nP :\n have managed to catch  \n\n\nQ :\n the Eskimos and Red Indians \n\n\nR :\n by a very difficulty method \n\n\nS :\n a few specimens of this aquatic animal \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QRPS", "optb": "SQPR", "optc": "SQRP", "optd": "QPSR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A French woman\n\n\n\nP :\n committed suicide\n\n\n\nQ :\n where she had put up\n\n\n\nR :\n who had come to Calcutta\n\n\n\nS :\n by jumping from the first floor balcony of the hotel\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PRQS", "optb": "QSRP", "optc": "RPSQ", "optd": "SRQP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The national unity of a free people\n\n\n\nP :\n to make it impracticable\n\n\n\nQ :\n for there to be an arbitrary administration\n\n\n\nR :\n depends upon a sufficiently even balance of political power\n\n\n\nS :\n against a revolutionary opposition that is irreconcilably opposed to it\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QRPS", "optb": "QRSP", "optc": "RPQS", "optd": "RSPQ", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The grocer\n\n\n\nP :\n did not listen to the protests of customer\n\n\n\nQ :\n who was in the habit of weighing less\n\n\n\nR :\n whom he had cheated\n\n\n\nS :\n with great audacity\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PRSQ", "optb": "QSPR", "optc": "QPRS", "optd": "PQSR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "They felt safer \n\n\nP :\n to watch the mountain \n\n\nQ :\n of more than five miles \n\n\nR :\n as they settled down \n\n\nS :\n from a distance \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPSQ", "optb": "RSQP", "optc": "PQSR", "optd": "PRSQ", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "People \n\n\nP :\n at his dispensary \n\n\nQ :\n went to him \n\n\nR :\n of all professions \n\n\nS :\n for medicine and treatment \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPRS", "optb": "RPQS", "optc": "RQSP", "optd": "QRPS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If you need help \n\n\nP :\n promptly and politely \n\n\nQ :\n ask for attendants \n\n\nR :\n to help our customers \n\n\nS :\n who have instructions \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SQPR", "optb": "QPSR", "optc": "QSRP", "optd": "SQRP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is easier \n\n\n\nP :\n to venture into space\n\n\n\nQ :\n for men\n\n\n\nR :\n beneath their feet\n\n\n\nS :\n than to explore\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QRPS", "optb": "QPSR", "optc": "PSRQ", "optd": "PQSR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was to be \n\n\nP :\n before their school examination \n\n\nQ :\n which was due to start \n\n\nR :\n the last expedition \n\n\nS :\n in a month's \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRQP", "optb": "RQSP", "optc": "RPQS", "optd": "SPRQ", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This time\n\n\n\nP :\n exactly what he had been told\n\n\n\nQ :\n the young man did\n\n\n\nR :\n beyond his dreams\n\n\n\nS :\n and the plan succeeded\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPRS", "optb": "QPSR", "optc": "PQSR", "optd": "QSRP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the darkness\n\n\n\nP :\n the long, narrow beard\n\n\n\nQ :\n was clearly visible with\n\n\n\nR :\n the tall stooping figure of the doctor\n\n\n\nS :\n and the aquiline nose\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RQPS", "optb": "PSQR", "optc": "RSQP", "optd": "QPRS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We have to\n\n\n\nP :\n as we see it \n\n\n\nQ :\n speak the truth\n\n\n\nR :\n there is falsehood and weakness\n\n\n\nS :\n even if all around us\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RQSP", "optb": "QRPS", "optc": "RSQP", "optd": "QPSR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When it began to rain suddenly on the first of January \n\n\nP :\n to celebrate the new year \n\n\nQ :\n we ran for shelter \n\n\nR :\n to the neighbouring house \n\n\nS :\n where many people had gathered \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QRPS", "optb": "PSQR", "optc": "PRSQ", "optd": "QRSP", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He told us that\n\n\n\nP :\n and enjoyed it immensely\n\n\n\nQ :\n in a prose translation\n\n\n\nR :\n he had read Milton\n\n\n\nS :\n which he had borrowed from his teacher\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RSQP", "optb": "QRPS", "optc": "RQSP", "optd": "RQPS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He knew that\n\n\n\nP :\n and then to save himself\n\n\n\nQ :\n was to save all the lives\n\n\n\nR :\n entrusted to his care\n\n\n\nS :\n the duty of a captain\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "SQRP", "optc": "SPRQ", "optd": "QSRP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is not, therefore\n\n\n\nP :\n that I pay a tribute\n\n\n\nQ :\n to conductors as a class\n\n\n\nR :\n with any feeling of unfriendliness\n\n\n\nS :\n to a particular member of that class\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "RQPS", "optc": "RSPQ", "optd": "PSRQ", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Of many artists\n\n\n\nP :\n those who impressed me the most\n\n\n\nQ :\n I was a child\n\n\n\nR :\n but those with unique personalities off stage\n\n\n\nS :\n were not always the successful ones\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRQP", "optb": "QRSP", "optc": "RSPQ", "optd": "QPSR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As a disease\n\n\n\nP :\n and breaks up marriages\n\n\n\nQ :\n accidents and suicides\n\n\n\nR :\n alcoholism leads to\n\n\n\nS :\n affecting all ages\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRPQ", "optb": "RPSQ", "optc": "SRQP", "optd": "RQPS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is easy to excuse \n\nP :\nbut it is hard \n\n\nQ :\nin a boy of fourteen  \n\n\nR :\nthe mischief of early childhood \n\n\nS :\nto tolerate even unavoidable faults  \n\n\n\r\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPQS", "optb": "QRSP", "optc": "QRPS", "optd": "RPSQ", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The majestic mahogany table\n\n\n\nP :\n belongs to an old prince\n\n\n\nQ :\n which has one leg missing\n\n\n\nR :\n who is no impoverished\n\n\n\nS :\n but not without some pride\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQSR", "optb": "QRSP", "optc": "PRSQ", "optd": "QPRS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Education is\n\n\n\nP :\n of the proper sense of responsibilities \n\n\n\nQ :\n the first need\n\n\n\nR :\n in a citizen\n\n\n\nS :\n for the development\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SQPR", "optb": "QSRP", "optc": "QSPR", "optd": "PQRS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It would\n\n\n\nP :\n appear from his statement\n\n\n\nQ :\n about the policy of management\n\n\n\nR :\n in dealing with the strike\n\n\n\nS :\n that he was quite in the dark\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPSQ", "optb": "PSQR", "optc": "RQPS", "optd": "PRQS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He was so kind and generous that \n\n\nP :\n he not only \n\n\nQ :\n made others do so \n\n\nR :\n but also \n\n\nS :\n helped them himself \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PSRQ", "optb": "SPQR", "optc": "PRSQ", "optd": "QPRS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "We went\n\n\n\nP :\n along the railway line\n\n\n\nQ :\n and had a right to\n\n\n\nR :\n where other people not allowed to go\n\n\n\nS :\n but daddy belonged to the railway\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPQS", "optb": "PRSQ", "optc": "RSQP", "optd": "PRQS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "There was\n\n\n\nP :\n needed for it everyday life\n\n\n\nQ :\n a time when each family\n\n\n\nR :\n for itself most of the things it\n\n\n\nS :\n actually produced\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QRSP", "optb": "RQPS", "optc": "RSPQ", "optd": "QSRP", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Little\n\n\n\nP :\n that he had been let down\n\n\n\nQ :\n stood by all these years\n\n\n\nR :\n did he realise\n\n\n\nS :\n by a colleague whom he had\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPSQ", "optb": "RSQP", "optc": "QSRP", "optd": "QSPR", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I saw that \n\n\nP :\n but seeing my host in this mood \n\n\nQ :\n I deemed it proper to take leave \n\n\nR :\n as I had frequently done before \n\n\nS :\n it had been my intention to pass the night there \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPSR", "optb": "QRPS", "optc": "SPQR", "optd": "SRPQ", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It is very easy\n\n\n\nP :\n a great deal more than one realises\n\n\n\nQ :\n may mean\n\n\n\nR :\n that a phrase that one does not quite understand\n\n\n\nS :\n to persuade oneself\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RSQP", "optb": "SPQR", "optc": "SRQP", "optd": "RQPS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I was\n\n\n\nP :\n and stay fro few days in Delhi\n\n\n\nQ :\n when my father told me\n\n\n\nR :\n very excited\n\n\n\nS :\n that I could go with him\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "RQSP", "optc": "QRSP", "optd": "SPQR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "work is the one thing\n\n\n\nP :\n and without it\n\n\n\nQ :\n that is necessary\n\n\n\nR :\n to keep the world going\n\n\n\nS :\n we should all die\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPSR", "optb": "RPQS", "optc": "SRPQ", "optd": "QRPS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The appearance \n\n\n\nP :\n this dinosaurs were at their peak \n\n\n\nQ :\n of the first mammals on the earth \n\n\n\nR :\n at the time when\n\n\n\nS :\n went almost unnoticed\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRPQ", "optb": "QSRP", "optc": "QRPS", "optd": "RPQS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "By this time\n\n\n\nP :\n at the railway station\n\n\n\nQ :\n reported mass looting\n\n\n\nR :\n reports of violence were flooding in\n\n\n\nS :\n which police dispatches\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RSPQ", "optb": "SPRQ", "optc": "SQRP", "optd": "RSQP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Then the women\n\nP :\nlamenting their evil desire \n\n\nQ :\nthat had brought \n\n\nR :\nwept loudly\n\n\nS :\nthis sorrow upon them \n\n\n\r\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPQS", "optb": "RQPS", "optc": "PQSR", "optd": "PRQS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Women\n\n\n\nP :\n till the other day\n\n\n\nQ :\n who were content being housewives\n\n\n\nR :\n about spending their time cooking\n\n\n\nS :\n now sound apologetic\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "RSPQ", "optc": "QPSR", "optd": "RQPS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Though he dialled frequently\n\n\n\nP :\n on telephone\n\n\n\nQ :\n my brother could not contact me\n\n\n\nR :\n and had left no information\n\n\n\nS :\n as I had gone out of office\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPRS", "optb": "SQRP", "optc": "QPSR", "optd": "SPQR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He said\n\n\n\nP :\n here is the cat\n\n\n\nQ :\n throughout the night\n\n\n\nR :\n which had been paying havoc with things\n\n\n\nS :\n that ate the rat\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PSQR", "optb": "PSRQ", "optc": "QPRS", "optd": "QRPS", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "He sat\n\n\n\nP :\n through the Town Hall Park\n\n\n\nQ :\n which flanked a path running\n\n\n\nR :\n under the boughs\n\n\n\nS :\n of a spreading tamarind tree\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQSR", "optb": "RSQP", "optc": "RSPQ", "optd": "PRSQ", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I don't remember \n\n\nP :\n I saw a man dying in front of a hospital  \n\n\nQ :\n but when I left lucknow in 1984 \n\n\nR :\n hit apparently by a fast moving car \n\n\nS :\n the exact date \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SQRP", "optb": "SQPR", "optc": "QRPS", "optd": "SPRQ", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "It was\n\n\n\nP :\n in keeping with my mood\n\n\n\nQ :\n a soft summer evening\n\n\n\nR :\n as I walked sedately\n\n\n\nS :\n in the direction of new house\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SRPQ", "optb": "QRPS", "optc": "QPRS", "optd": "SQPR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All such students\n\n\n\nP :\n get success\n\n\n\nQ :\n who are honest and hard-working\n\n\n\nR :\n and recognition\n\n\n\nS :\n in very walk of life\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "SPRQ", "optb": "PRQS", "optc": "QPRS", "optd": "PSRQ", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The master \n\n\nP :\n who was very loyal to him \n\n\nQ :\n punished the servant \n\n\nR :\n without giving any valid reason \n\n\nS :\n when he left the work unfinished \n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RQPS", "optb": "RQSP", "optc": "QPSR", "optd": "QRPS", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With her body\n\n\n\nP :\n dragging her unwilling feet\n\n\n\nQ :\n weak and infirm\n\n\n\nR :\n doubled with age\n\n\n\nS :\n she persisted in her mission\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "PQRS", "optb": "QPRS", "optc": "RQPS", "optd": "SRPQ", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "P: We must read\n\n\n\nP :\n if we want to absorb the fruits of great literature\n\n\n\nQ :\n but with concentration\n\n\n\nR :\n them not as we do cricket stories\n\n\n\nS :\nundefined\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "QPSR", "optb": "PSQR", "optc": "PRSQ", "optd": "PRQS", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I enclose\n\n\n\nP :\n and the postage\n\n\n\nQ :\n a postal order\n\n\n\nR :\n the price of books\n\n\n\nS :\n which will cover\n\n\n\nThe Proper sequence should be:", "opta": "RPSQ", "optb": "QSPR", "optc": "QSRP", "optd": "QPSR", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}